You just couldn't
bear solitude, that's all.
貴様は孤独に耐えられなかっただけだ
Who isn't alone in this society?
この社会に孤独でない人間など誰がいる
In this world where everyone is
watched over by the system
誰もがシステムに見守られ
システムの規範に沿って生きる世界には
and lives within the system's standards,
a community isn't necessary.
人の輪なんて必要ない
Everyone just lives in their own little cell,
みんな 小さな独房の中で
and the system tames them by giving
them each their own personal serenity.
自分だけの安らぎに飼いならされているだけだ
You're the same too, right,
Shinya Kogami?
君だってそうだろ 狡噛慎也
No one accepted your justice.
誰も君の正義を認めなかった
No one understood your anger, either.
君の怒りを理解しなかった
だから君は信頼にも友情にも背を向けて
So you turned your
back on trust and friendships,
and you even abandoned
the only place you could belong to
たった一つ 自分に残された居場所さえかなぐり捨てて
in order to come this far.
ここまで来た
And yet, you laugh at my solitude?
そんな君が僕の孤独を笑うのか
But you know... I highly value
one who doesn't fear solitude...
だがね…僕はむしろ評価する
孤独を恐れない者を
...you, who turned
your solitude into a weapon.
孤独を武器にしてきた君を
#22 Perfect World
I would like to show
Cut open my skull
Look into my head
I don’t
I don't know why I'm so harsh
know why I’m so harsh
I could be so brash
I'm going to clash
I’m going to clash
’cause I feel
'Cause I feel
I can always show my everything to you
I can always show
my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear
Lend my ear
Voices inside
voices inside
one link to join it all
One link to join it all again
Again
’cause I feel
'Cause I feel
I can always show my everything to you
I can always show
my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear
Lend my ear
Voices inside
voices inside
one link to join it all
One link to join it all
So it goes again
so it goes again
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:死树懒  校对:西西    时间轴:Maize     压制：娜夏
You never learn, do you, Kogami?
お前は成長がないな…狡噛
Hold it right there.
そこまでです
Mr. Kogami...
狡噛さん…
...please don't move.
動かないでください
Makishima is nearby, too.
槙島もすぐそばにいるぞ
Yes, I know. I'll capture him, too.
分かってます
あの男も捕まえます
Are you going to handcuff me
here and go after him all by yourself?
ここで俺にワッパをかけて
後はあんた一人で槙島を追う気か
I'm not that reckless.
そこまで無謀じゃありませんよ 私
This is locked in Paralyzer
mode with the safety unlocked.
セーフティーは解除されたままで
パラライザーで固定されてます
You should be able to use it, too.
今のあなたにも使えるはずです
Please give me a hand.
手伝ってください
We'll just paralyze
Makishima using Paralyzer.
槙島は パラライザーで麻痺させるだけ
If you try anything beyond that,
I'll shoot your leg.
それ以上のことをしようとしたら
私はあなたの足を撃ちます
I'm surprised.
驚いたね
I thought you'd get tougher...
タフになると思っちゃいたが…
...but I do think
you could be a bit nicer.
まだもう少し可愛げがあってもよかったと思うぜ
You're trying not to kill
Makishima no matter what because...
あんたがどうあっても 槙島を殺さないのは…
Because it's illegal.
Because I can't overlook a crime.
違法だからです
犯罪を見過ごせないからです
Why are you going
that far to obey the law
悪人を裁けず
人を守れない法律を
when that law can neither judge
a criminal nor protect people?
何でそうまでして守り通そうとするんだ
The law doesn't protect people.
People protect the law.
法が人を守るんじゃない
人が法を守るんです
People have always detested evil and
sought out a righteous way of living.
これまで 悪を憎んで
正しい生き方を探し求めてきた人々の思いが…
Their feelings... The accumulation
of those peoples' feelings are the law.
その積み重ねが法なんです
They're neither the
provisions nor the system.
それは 条文でもシステムでもない
They're the fragile
and irreplaceable feelings
誰もが心の中に抱えてる
that everyone carries in their hearts.
脆くて掛け替えのない思いです
Compared to the
power of anger and hatred,
怒りや憎しみの力に比べたら
they are something that
can quite easily break down.
どうしようもなく簡単に壊れてしまうものなんです
People have prayed for
a better world throughout time.
だから より良い世界を創ろうとした過去全ての人たちの祈りを
In order for those prayers
to continue to hold meaning,
無意味にしてしまわないために…
we have to try our best to
protect it to the very end.
それは最後まで 頑張って守り通さなきゃいけないんです
We just can't give up on it.
諦めちゃいけないんです
If there ever comes a time when
everyone feels that way,
いつか
誰もがそう思うような時代が来れば…
その時はシビュラシステムなんて消えちまうだろう
the Sibyl System
will probably disappear.
There'll no longer be any
latent criminals or Enforcers.
潜在犯も 執行官もいなくなるだろう
But...
だが…
Tsk!
Akane!
朱
I wish...
いい加減
...you guys would
stop insulting us... already.
僕たちを侮辱するのは…
止めてほしい
I see... You are...
そうか…
君は…
N-No...
だ…駄目…
This is just between the two of us.
これは 俺とあいつだけの問題なんだ
Mr. Kogami!
狡噛さーん！
Everyone is alone.
誰だって孤独だ
Everyone is empty.
誰だって虚ろだ
People no longer have need of others.
もう 誰も他人を必要としない
You can always find
a spare for any talent.
どんな才能も
スペアが見つかる
Any relationship can be replaced.
どんな関係でも取り換えが利く
I had gotten
bored of a world like that.
そんな世界に
飽きていた
But for some reason...
でも どうしてかな
...the thought that someone other than
you might kill me never occurred to me.
僕が君以外の誰かに殺される光景は…
どうしても 思い浮かばないんだ
Say, what do you think, Kogami...
なあ どうなんだ
狡噛
...after this, will you be able
to find a replacement for me?
君はこの後 僕の代わりを見つけられるのか
Well, I sure hope not.
いいや
もう二度とごめんだね
Long before... they had ever met,
二人は
初めて出会うより以前から…
I think this destiny awaited them.
ああなる運命だったんだろう
They were not like
ships passing in the night.
すれ違っていたわけでもない
It wasn't like they
didn't understand each other.
分かり合えなかったわけでもない
They understood each
other better than anyone else,
彼らは誰よりもお互いを理解し…
and each was focused
solely on the other.
相手のことだけを見詰めていた…
Mr. Kogami...
狡噛さん…
The outcome of the attempt to capture
Shogo Makishima was quite regrettable.
槙島聖護の身柄確保については
大変遺憾な結果となりました
Does that mean I'm no longer needed?
これで私は用済みってこと
常守朱の能力評価については
We have no choice but to lower
our evaluation of your abilities.
下方修正を余儀なくされます
However, that does not mean that
the value of your existence turns negative.
…が それによって
あなたの存在価値がマイナスに転じるわけではありません
Rather, when it comes
to managing the Sibyl System,
むしろシビュラシステムの運営上
you are still an individual
of outstanding value.
あなたは依然として 特出した価値を持つ個人です
What do you mean?
どういう意味よ
あなたの健康かつ強靱なサイコパスと
You have a healthy, strong Psycho-Pass,
as well as a clear
mind and judgment.
明晰な頭脳 判断力は来たるべき新たな時代の市民に示す指標として
We can say that your qualities
are as close to ideal as they come
for serving as an example to
the citizens of the coming new era.
十分な理想型といえます
そして あなたはシビュラシステムに対し
And, you hold an emotional
antipathy that is completely contrary
完全に相反する感情的反感と理論的評価を抱いており
to your theoretical
assessment of the Sibyl System,
and that conflict continues to exist.
今なおその葛藤は継続している
If we can establish a means
of winning you over to our side,
そんなあなたを懐柔する手法が確立できたなら
we will be able to
obtain valuable sample data
我々は 社会の統制を次の段階に進める上で
貴重なサンプルデータを獲得できることでしょう
for taking the governance of
society to the next level.
What are you up to?
何を企んでいるの
Considering public opinion,
目下のところ 世論の情勢を鑑みて
the true form of the Sibyl System
is currently completely kept secret.
シビュラシステムの実体は
完全に秘匿されています
短期的戦略としての隠蔽工作は 現状ではまだ容易ですが
At this point, covering it up is still
a simple strategy in the short term.
長期的視野に立った場合
However, as a long-term strategy,
this is never desirable.
これは決して望ましい方針ではない
いずれ我々は 偽らざる姿を公のものとするべきなのです
We should eventually
make our true form public.
全ての市民がシビュラの正体を認識し 了解した上で
Creating an environment where
every citizen enjoys and accepts
我々による統制を享受するようになる環境を整えること
our governance after they
become aware of our true form...
この課題の達成は
Achieving this task will solidify
the stability and prosperity
将来の人類社会に
より盤石な安定と繁栄をもたらすことでしょう
of the future human society.
我々が引き続きあなたの動向を観察し 解析することは
Continuing to observe
and analyze your movements
will provide us with valuable
hints on how to build a methodology
未来の市民を懐柔し 順応させる方法論を構築する
for winning over the citizens in
the future and getting them to adapt.
貴重な手掛かりとなるのです
You think it'll go so smoothly?
そんなにうまくいくと思ってるの
機密保守を脅かす兆候がないかぎり
As long as you don't show
any signs of jeopardizing our secret,
あなたの生命と行動の自由は保障されるでしょう
your life and your freedom of
action will be guaranteed.
協力的態度を期待します
We hope you will cooperate with us.
自己保存の欲求に従えば
If you are to follow your desire for
self-preservation, there is only one choice.
あなたに選択の余地はないはずです
そうね
Yeah, I don't want to die in vain,
犬死にはごめんだし
今の世の中がシビュラ抜きでは成り立たないのも事実だし
and it's true that the current
society cannot hold without Sibyl.
あなたの順法精神に基づく判断は信頼に値します
We feel that we can trust in your
respect for the law when you make decisions.
Do you know the most
demeaning thing you can do
尊くあるべきはずの法を
何よりも貶めることは何だか 分かってる
to the law that should be sacred?
それはね
Creating and administering
a law that is unworthy of protection.
守るに値しない法律をつくり 運用することよ
人間を甘く見ないことね
You shouldn't underestimate humans.
私たちはいつだって
We're always aiming for a better society.
より良い社会を目指してる
いつか誰かがこの部屋の電源を落としにやって来るわ
Someone will come to this
room some day to turn off the power.
きっと新しい道を見つけてみせる
We will find a new path for sure.
シビュラシステム
Sibyl System,
you guys have no future!
あなたたちに未来なんてないのよ
Akane Tsunemori...
常守朱
抗いなさい
Fight...
Struggle...
苦悩しなさい
...so that it will help us to evolve.
我々に進化をもたらす糧として…
2 months later
やあ 久しぶり…
Hey, it's been a while...
I came to talk to you today...
今日は報告に来た
身の振り方を決めたんでね
since I decided
what I'm going to do next.
犯罪係数
My Crime Coefficient went up to 140.
１４０までいったよ
もう回復の見込みはない
There's no longer a chance of recovery.
だが 隔離施設で腐ってるのも性に合わなくてね…
But it's not in my nature to sit
around and mope in the isolation facility.
結局 古巣に戻ることにした
So I decided to go
back to where I used to work.
違う道を進めとあんたは言ったが
You told me to take a different path.
ご期待には添えなかったわけだ
Guess I didn't live
up to your expectations.
どこまでも 親不孝な息子だよ
I'm a bad son in every respect, aren't I?
でもな 不思議と後悔はしてないんだ
But strangely enough,
I don't have any regrets.
デカなんて碌なもんじゃない
There's nothing
good about being a detective.
Even so, it's a job
that someone needs to do.
それでも
誰かが引き受けなきゃならない仕事だ
そうだろ
Right... Dad?
親父
Sorry for troubling you.
手間をかけさせてすまない
いえ 執行官の外出に同伴するのは
That's okay. It's my duty to
accompany an Enforcer when they go out.
服務規程ですから
Unlike Kagari, at least
my dad was able to get a grave.
ああして墓があるだけ 縢よりはましだ
二係の調査 打ち切られたんだろ
Division 2 was told to stop
their investigation on him, right?
ええ
Yes.
I bet Kagari isn't alive anymore.
きっと縢は もうこの世にいない
上層部はその確証をつかんだ上で
I'm sure the top brass found evidence
of that, but they're trying to sweep it
発表せずにうやむやにしてる
under the rug and
keep it from the public.
狡噛さんは どこにいるんでしょうね
I wonder where Mr. Kogami is.
When the collar comes
off of such a wild hunting dog,
あれだけ獰猛な猟犬から首輪が外れたら
それはもうオオカミと変わらない
he becomes no different from a wolf.
むしろ野生に戻った分
Now that he's back in the wild...
伸び伸びとやってるかもしれん
...he might rather be living
a free and easygoing life.
Would living like that be relaxing?
そんな…気楽なものでしょうか
執行官だったころのあいつが
It's not like he was living a
relaxing life when he was an Enforcer, right?
気楽にやってたわけでもないだろう
He was a persevering, cunning man
who didn't know when to give up.
しぶとくて 狡猾で
諦めの悪い男だった
No matter how bad the situation,
he'll always pull through.
どんな過酷な状況だろうと あいつはきっと切り抜ける
The one I'm more concerned about...
is you, Inspector Tsunemori.
むしろ心配なのは 常守監視官
あなたの方だ
What? Me?
えっ…私
You are ever the worrier, Mr. Ginoza.
相変わらず心配性ですね 宜野座さんは…
過去よりも未来に目を向けよう
Let's look at the future,
rather than the past.
新任の監視官
A new Inspector will be
assigned tomorrow, right?
明日には着任するんだろう
異例の人事ですよね
It's unusual to hire a minor, isn't it?
未成年の登用なんて…
We're partially responsible for that.
俺たちにも 責任の一端はある
ところで つまんないこと聞いてもいいですか
By the way,
may I ask you a trivial question?
何だ
What is it?
Were you wearing glasses for show?
眼鏡…ダテだったんですか
What?
自分の顔が嫌いでね
I don't like how my face looks,
especially my eyes.
特に目元が…
But I don't care
about that anymore, so...
だがもう
どうでもよくなったんだ 今は…
Division 1 underwent
a sea change, didn't it?
一係も様変わりしちゃったわよね
Shu, Masa and Shinya...
秀君に征さん 慎也君…
They're all gone.
みんないなくなっちゃった
It means that old-fashioned
guys are not suited for this job.
時代遅れな男たちには
この仕事は向いてないってこと
Isn't calling them
old-fashioned a bit harsh?
時代遅れはひどいんじゃない
Why don't you call them romantics?
ロマンチストって言ってあげなよ
Could that be a comfort to them?
それで慰めになるのかしらね あいつら…
This is the CID,
part of the Public Safety Bureau.
こちらは公安局刑事課です
Access to this block is
currently restricted to ensure safety.
現在 この区画は安全のために
立ち入りが制限されています
Excuse me!
Are you Inspector Tsunemori?
あの 監視官の常守さんですか
ええ 配属早々に事件とは災難ね
Yes.
What bad luck that you have to deal
with an incident right after you got posted.
本日付で刑事課に配属になりました
I'm Mika Shimotsuki.
I've been assigned to the Criminal
Investigation Department as of today!
霜月美佳です
よろしくお願いします
Pleased to meet you!
悪いけど
Sorry, but the CID
is very short on manpower.
刑事課の人手不足は深刻なの
フォローはするけど 新米扱いはできない
So I'll help you out but
I can't treat you like a newbie.
承知しています
I'm aware of that.
I'm looking forward to the work.
望むところです
Good response.
いい返事ね
That's...
あれは
The guys you're about to
meet are humans just like us,
今から会う連中は
同じ人間ではあるけれど
but they'll deal with crimes using
criteria for judgment different from yours.
君とはまったく違う判断基準で犯罪に対処する
彼らの行動は
Their actions sometimes
may be beyond your comprehension.
時として君の理解を超えたものになるかもしれない
信頼する分だけ用心もしなさい
Trust them, but at the same time,
be cautious of them.
嘗めてかかると大ケガをする
If you underestimate them,
you'll get seriously hurt.
They're what we call "Enforcers."
They'll be your subordinates.
それが執行官
君が預かる部下たちよ
Dominator Portable Psychological
Diagnosis and Suppression System
「携帯型心理診断」
「鎮圧執行システム·ドミネーター起動しました」
has been activated.
誰かを愛することなんて
There's no way that I could love someone
できるわけなくって
But I want someone to love me
だけど誰かに愛されたくて
変わらない昨日がずっと続いたとしても
Even if yesterday could
continue unchanging into forever
You and I would never get anywhere
どこにも行けやしないんだ
私とキミ
神さま どこへ行ってしまったの ねえ
God... where did you go?
返事はなくて　いつだってそうだよ
I don't hear any response,
but that's how it always is
Are you still here?
You'll never walk alone
あなたと行く
I'll go with you
No matter the sin,
I'll bear the burden for you
どんな罪も
背負ってあげる
I'll walk an uncharted path
道なき道を
歩いてくの
All alone with you
あなたと二人で
Swann's Way
The chain of justice... the system... never ends...